<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-10T15:10:52-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Cyber Turtle</title><subtitle>A cybersecurity student writing about cybersecurity things</subtitle><entry><title type="html">30 Days of THM: Day 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/13/day_five_thm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Days of THM: Day 5" /><published>2024-06-13T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-13T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/13/day_five_thm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/13/day_five_thm.html"><![CDATA[<p>30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 5
Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to build a streak of learning through the website TryHackMe. Today I am picking up right where I left off on the Complete Beginner Path and tackle Cryptography.</p>

<p>The first room is Hashing — Crypto 101, a kind of introduction to the concept of cryptography. It goes over some definitions, and it goes over hashing. Hashing is taking an input of any size and creating a ‘digest’ of the input, of a fixed size. The output needs to be unique (even changing a little bit of the text should give out a new hash). A hash is, in theory, irreversible, but some hashes are more secure than others.</p>

<p>Passwords are stored in hashes, which is why they are useful to know about from a security perspective.</p>

<p>It then gives a few examples of how to find some hashes, some online and through other tools.</p>

<p>The next room is all about the password cracking tool John the Ripper. John the Ripper is a tool you can use in order to crack passwords, if you have the hash of the password. The room goes over a lot of the different ways to use John, and you will get a little bit of more experience with the tool through some challenges.</p>

<p>The final room of this section is Encryption — Crypto 101. This room is extremely theory heavy, and one of the first questions you ‘answer’ is to not complain about how theory heavy it is.</p>

<p>You are once again introduced to some definitions, but this room will go into the why of cryptography. Cryptography is essential for ensuring security in pretty much any context involving a computer. Doing this room also stresses the importance of the modulo operator (think something like 65 % 6) in cryptography.</p>

<p>This room also goes over the different kinds of encryption, keys and asymmetric cryptography, digital signatures, and a whole lot more. This is probably one of the more theory heavy rooms I’ve done so far, but it was good to learn a lot more about a topic I wasn’t too familiar with.</p>

<p>This section wasn’t too time consuming, but it did require a lot more thinking to be done than previous sections.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 5 Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to build a streak of learning through the website TryHackMe. Today I am picking up right where I left off on the Complete Beginner Path and tackle Cryptography.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">30 Days of THM: Day 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/11/day_four_thm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Days of THM: Day 4" /><published>2024-06-11T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-11T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/11/day_four_thm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/11/day_four_thm.html"><![CDATA[<p>30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 4
Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to build up a streak of 30 days of learning using the popular website, TryHackMe. Today is Day 4, and I am still on the complete beginners pathway. Yesterday was the Network Exploitation Basics section. Today, I am doing the Web Hacking Fundamentals section, and I am excited to continue on this path.</p>

<p>The first section is the basic introduction of how websites work. The two major components are the front end (what you see), and the back end (the server processing the requests your browser makes). When you go to a website, you make a request through a browser. The browser can be called the client. The website’s server responds to that request. It goes over HTML, Javascript, and an HTML injection.</p>

<p>The second section goes over HTTP in detail. The Hyper Text Transfer Protocol, this is how we communicate with websites. There is also HTTPS, which is the secure version of HTTP (meaning it is encrypted).</p>

<p>It goes over HTTP requests, the different methods (GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE), the status codes, headers, cookies, and how to make requests.</p>

<p>And then the next room goes over the security tool Burp Suite. This room is all about learning what Burp Suite is and what it does, while future rooms (that are not part of this section) are more about using Burp Suite. At it’s most basic form, Burp Suite allows a user to intercept an HTTP request and manipulate it. There are a few version of Burp Suite, but the free one, Burp Suite Community Edition, is the one used in this room.</p>

<p>The features of Burp Suite Community are:</p>
<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Proxy: allows the interception and modification of HTTP requests.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Repeater: allows the capture and resending of multiple requests.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Intruder: allows spraying endpoints with requests, common in brute-force attacks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Decoder: Can decode captured information and encode payloads.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Comparer: Can compare two pieces of data at either word or byte-level.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Sequencer: Analyzes the randomness of things like cookies.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>The room goes into the basics of Burp Suite, how to use it and configure it, but future rooms will go into greater detail.</p>

<p>The next room goes into detail about the OWASP Top 10, the 10 most critcal web vulnerabilities. Those vulnerabilities are:</p>
<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Broken Access Control: a user being able to view something on a website that they aren’t supposed to view. For example, being able to view an administrative page.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Cryptographic Failure: Cryptography ensures that any data, either being sent or being stored, is encrypted.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Injection: When the application interprets user controlled input as commands or parameters. SQL Injections and command injections are common types of injections.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Insecure Design: The design of the application itself is flawed.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Security Misconfiguration: There is a part of the application that has been configured incorrectly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Vulnerable and Outdated Components: Using a program with a well-known vulnerability.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Identification and Authentication Failures: Gaining access to other user’s accounts through weak authentication.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Software and Data Integrity Failures: The data has been modified in some way.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Security Logging and Monitoring Failures: No logs to determine what an attacker might have done.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Server-side request forgery: An attacker causes a server to send requests to unintended destinations.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>The next room is OWASP Juice Shop, which goes over the different vulnerabilities in a web application. This one is kind of like a tutorial of a vulnerable machine, where you are being pointed to on where to go next. This also gives you more experience with Burp Suite.</p>

<p>The neat thing about this room is that it also has a score board, and if you want you can solve more challenges after the room is complete.</p>

<p>The next room is Upload Vulnerabilities, which is all about file upload vulnerabilities in websites. This section went into great detail about all the ways mechanisms for uploading files can be exploited. How files can be overwritten, used for RCE, how websites use client-side and server-side filtering to make sure the proper files are uploaded and how that can be worked around. It went over file signatures and how to manipulate that (for the challenge I used the Wikipedia article here).</p>

<p>And the final project in this room is using all of the above content to breach a room with no hand holding. I found this part to be really difficult, but when I finally got it I felt so good about it.</p>

<p>The final part of this section is Pickle Rick, a CTF where you have to find three flags in order to turn Rick back into a human.</p>

<p>As a bit of a mini-waltkthrough, here is mine:</p>

<p>Once I had the machine setup, I went to the web application to poke around. I opened up the page and looked at the HTML and found the username.</p>

<p>I then used nmap to look at the first 1000 ports, and saw that port 22 (ssh) and port 80 (http) were open.</p>

<p>With a few more scans of the website, I saw that there was a robots.txt file.</p>

<p>I have no idea what this means, I have seen maybe two episodes of Rick and Morty in my life. But, maybe a password? I tried to use ssh to get into the machine, but that was denied. So maybe there was another thing?</p>

<p>With a little bit more enumeration, I saw there was an /assets directory. In there, there was a file called portal.jpg. A little bit more enumeration showed me there was a /portal.php page. I imputed the credentials I found and was in.</p>

<p>A place I could execute some code. I first ran whoami, pwd, and ls to figure out which user I was, the directory I was in, and the contents of that directory, and I saw the first flag.</p>

<p>I tried to open the file, but I found that was disabled. At least with the cat command. With another command, I was able to open it. I used that same command to open the file clue.txt which says to look around the file system. I found the second ingredient in the home directory. I found the last ingredient in the root directory.</p>

<p>This section was a pretty involved section, and it did take me a lot longer to complete than just a day. I will still consider this ‘day 4’ because ’30 Sections of TryHackMe’ just didn’t sound as good.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 4 Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to build up a streak of 30 days of learning using the popular website, TryHackMe. Today is Day 4, and I am still on the complete beginners pathway. Yesterday was the Network Exploitation Basics section. Today, I am doing the Web Hacking Fundamentals section, and I am excited to continue on this path.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">30 Days of THM: Day 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/08/day_three_thm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Days of THM: Day 3" /><published>2024-06-08T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-08T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/08/day_three_thm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/08/day_three_thm.html"><![CDATA[<p>30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 3
Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section of TryHackMe every day for 30 days. Today is the 3rd day of the challenge, and I will be picking up right where I left off on the Complete Beginner Pathway. This is not a writeup or a walkthrough, this is more of a way of tracking my own progress and documenting my own thoughts as I go on.</p>

<p>Today’s section is the Network Exploitation Basics section. This section is an overview of networking. It isn’t promising to teach you everything about networking, just a rough overview to get you started.</p>

<p>And the first room is exactly that, titled Introductory Networking. The first section of this room, after the introduction, is all about the OSI model. The OSI model is a way of abstracting the way information is sent across networks. There are 7 layers of the OSI model:</p>

<p>Physical: the hardware and electrical pulses
Data Link: Responsible for physical addressing (think MAC addresses)
Network: Responsible for logical addressing (think IP addresses)
Transport: chooses which protocol to send the data over. TCP- for cases when you need every last bit data to be sent over — think web pages, file downloads. Or UDP — for cases when a little bit of packet loss is acceptable — think live video streaming.
Session: sets up and maintains the connection.
Presentation: receives the data from the application layer and translates the data into a standardised format.
Application: provides applications an interface to transmit data.
I remember the OSI model through the helpful mnemonic, Please Do Not Throw Sausage Pizza Away.</p>

<p>The next section goes over encapsulation, which is the process of data moving down the OSI model, starting from the application layer and moving all the way down to the physical layer. At each layer, a header is added. De-encapsulation is the reverse, and that happens when a computer is on the receiving end.</p>

<p>The next section after that goes over the TCP/IP model, which is like the OSI in that it is a way of abstracting the way information moves across a network. It also goes over the three way TCP handshake, which consists of a SYN, a SYN ACK, and an ACK. And the next few sections go over some networking tools like ping, traceroute, whois, and dig.</p>

<p>The next room is Nmap. Nmap is a tool used for security and port scanning, and it is really useful for information gathering about a target. If you want to know what services are running on a target, what kind of machine they’re using, what ports are open, nmap is the tool to use.</p>

<p>This room goes into a lot of detail about nmap, and there is a lot to know about it. For some of the answers, I was going to either the man page or nmap.org to learn more about it. There are a lot of things that no one is going to be able to memorize, so knowing about those two resources are beneficial.</p>

<p>The third room is Network Services. This room goes over different services and the various misconfigurations those services can potentially have. First on the list to go over is Server Message Block, a communication protocol meant for sharing access to resources on a server. After learning a little bit about it, I went on to enumerate a machine running SMB, and learned a little bit about exploiting it to get a flag.</p>

<p>The next protocol is telnet, a protocol that allows for remote access similar to ssh. Unlike ssh though, telnet is unencrypted. This part goes through much of the same thing, where I first learn about the protocol, enumerate a machine that has it, and then exploit it. The last protocol in this section is FTP, file transfer protocol.</p>

<p>And the final section is a ‘sequel’ to the last one, where I also go over some protocols, go through enumerating a machine with the protocol, and learn how to exploit it. First up is NFS, network file system. NFS is a protocol that allows users to access files as if they were local to their systems. NFS does this by mounting the files on a server.</p>

<p>The next protocol it goes over is SMTP, Simple Mail Transfer Protocol. SMTP is responsible for three things:</p>

<p>Verifies who is sending emails
Sends the outgoing mail
Sends it back if it does not get delivered</p>

<p>It works with POP, post office protocol, and IMAP, internet message access protocol, which are used for retrieving emails. The last part is going over, enumerating, and exploiting MySQL, a database management system.</p>

<p>This section was a lot of fun, and a lot more challenging than the last two days. It was a great introduction to networking protocols, and I really liked using the last two sections to learn a little bit about each and how to exploit them.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 3 Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section of TryHackMe every day for 30 days. Today is the 3rd day of the challenge, and I will be picking up right where I left off on the Complete Beginner Pathway. This is not a writeup or a walkthrough, this is more of a way of tracking my own progress and documenting my own thoughts as I go on.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">30 Days of THM: Day 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/Day_one_thm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Days of THM: Day 1" /><published>2024-06-05T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-05T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/Day_one_thm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/Day_one_thm.html"><![CDATA[<p>30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 1
Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section in TryHackMe every single day for the next 30 days. The purpose of this is to build up a streak of learning, and also as a review of things that may have slipped my mind. This is Day 1, so I am starting right at the beginning and I am going to work my way through.</p>

<p>The path I selected is the Complete Beginner Pathway. I have used TryHackMe before, but I want to get the complete experience of someone coming to this website with no experience.</p>

<p>The first section in this pathway is the Complete Beginner Introduction. The first section, aptly called Tutorial, goes over how to use the AttackBox, which is the machine a user would use while learning. You start up the machine, wait a few minutes for it to load, and then follow a simple set of instructions to get your first flag. A flag is a string of text that you get after completing cybersecurity challenges. Once you submit your flag, then you complete the room and move on to the next one.</p>

<p>All of the other rooms follow the same formula, although obviously some of the other rooms won’t be as easy as the first one.</p>

<p>After you finish Tutorial, the next room is Starting Out In Cyber Sec. This room goes over two different sides of cybersecurity: offensive and defensive. Both sides require an analytical mind, but there are some kety differences. Offensive security is all about attacking different applications and discovering where there are vulnerabilities. Defensive security is all about discovering and fixing those vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>After reading the description and answering some questions, you move on to the next room, Introductory Researching. The aim of this room is to encourage research into the field. Everyone in cybersecurity needs to research, no one knows everything.</p>

<p>Since the room required research, I aimed to do that for every question even if I knew the answers. It was kind of hard to do that with Google’s AI able to answer everything, so I had to improvise a little, to try to ask questions that someone who had just stumbled upon these subjects for the first time would ask.</p>

<p>I thought this was a pretty effective way of keeping me on my toes, because even for questions that I knew the answer to, understanding the why was an equally important concept. I thought this room did an excellent job emphasizing that.</p>

<p>Although in my research I did find people who just posted the questions to Quora or Reddit or some other website, and I do wonder if that is a form of cheating.</p>

<p>This room goes through general research questions and more specific vulnerability research, and using the Linux man command to figure out how to do specific things.</p>

<p>Overall this room was a great introduction to TryHackMe, and I had a lot of fun doing some research and learning a little bit more.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 1 Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section in TryHackMe every single day for the next 30 days. The purpose of this is to build up a streak of learning, and also as a review of things that may have slipped my mind. This is Day 1, so I am starting right at the beginning and I am going to work my way through.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">30 Days of THM: Day 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/day_two_thm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="30 Days of THM: Day 2" /><published>2024-06-05T06:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-06-05T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/day_two_thm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/tryhackme/2024/06/05/day_two_thm.html"><![CDATA[<p>30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 2
Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section of TryHackMe every single day for 30 days. Today is the second day of this challenge I gave myself, and I am going to be picking up where I left off with the Complete Beginner Pathway. This series is not going to be a walkthrough or a writeup, but more a way of tracking my progress and some thoughts I have about the website along the way. If you are looking for answers, then you can stop reading here.</p>

<p>Yesterday, I worked on the tutorial section. Today, the section I will be working on is Linux Fundamentals. Linux is a free and open source operating system based on the UNIX operating system, and it is named after creator Linus Torvalds. Most people will know about MacOS or Windows, but Linux is important to know because so many servers run on it. Free means you can use it without paying for it, and open source means anyone can work on it.</p>

<p>Part One is a good introduction to Linux and its command line. It gives a bit of background about the operating system, and then it allows you to deploy a virtual machine so you can mess around with it. The machine you’re given is a Command Line Interface, which is just you typing commands. So no clicking around, just you and the commands you know.</p>

<p>Part Two explores SSH, Secure Shell. That is a way of remotely accessing another machine, very important in the context of hacking. In this room we open up the AttackBox and use the ‘ssh’ command in order to access another machine. It also introduces a few flags and switches that you would want to use to add more functionality to the commands. For example, the ‘ls’ command has the ‘-a’ argument, which will list all files in the directory, including any hidden files.</p>

<p>This section also goes over a few other commands, like ‘touch’, ‘mv’, and ‘file’, as well as file permissions. File permissions tell users who can do what with a file. Can they read it, write to it, execute it?</p>

<p>It also goes over the common directories and what goes in them. The /etc directory has files important to the operating system, including the ‘passwd’ and ‘shadow’ files, which contains the passwords for all the users on the system. The /var directory, which contains data from different applications running. /var/log is an important directory as it contains all the log files. The root directory, which is just the home for the root user. And the /tmp directory, short for temporary, which is world-writeable and anything in there will disappear after being restarted.</p>

<p>The third section introduces some other stuff that is useful to know. It goes over text editors, such as Nano and Vim. It goes over downloading files and transferring files using ‘wget’ and ‘scp’ respectively. Starting up webservers (it recommended I read the documentation for python’s HTTPServer module).</p>

<p>The next few sections I really appreciated because this stuff never really came easily to me. It goes over processes. How to look at processes using the ‘ps’ and ‘ps aux’ commands, starting and killing processes, and backgrounding and foregrounding. It goes over package management and system logs.</p>

<p>This section was an excellent introduction to Linux, and it was nice to go over all of this again.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="tryhackme" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[30 Days of TryHackMe: Day 2 Welcome to 30 Days of TryHackMe, where I try to complete a section of TryHackMe every single day for 30 days. Today is the second day of this challenge I gave myself, and I am going to be picking up where I left off with the Complete Beginner Pathway. This series is not going to be a walkthrough or a writeup, but more a way of tracking my progress and some thoughts I have about the website along the way. If you are looking for answers, then you can stop reading here.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Experience Working the Night Shift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/personal/2023/10/08/graveyard_shift.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Experience Working the Night Shift" /><published>2023-10-08T18:53:33-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-08T18:53:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/personal/2023/10/08/graveyard_shift</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/personal/2023/10/08/graveyard_shift.html"><![CDATA[<p>It was November of 2017. Eleven months after graduating from college, I was working in the job of nobody’s dreams: retail stock associate. Holiday season was fast approaching, and my manager at work approached me to ask a simple question.</p>

<p>“Are you available for overnights?”</p>

<p>“Yeah, absolutely,” I replied, with a sense of unease in my stomach.</p>

<p>I had just gotten into the stock team after weeks of being on the sales floor, and I was eager to stay there. I hated talking to people, and the crazy expectations of the sales floor were too stressful for me to handle. This was my first job out of college, and I was desperate to make a good impression. It won’t be permanent, I told myself.</p>

<p>And it was not permanent, but it was an experience I won’t forget. From late November of 2017 to April of 2018, I was working the graveyard shift at a retail job in a mall. Our job was to open boxes of shipment, put sensors on the merchandise in the boxes, and either place the new clothes on the sales floor or find room for it in the stockroom. The shift time was from 11 PM to 7 AM, sometimes going longer.</p>

<p>I remember being told it was going to be a temporary thing just for the holidays. If there’s one thing that anybody who has worked retail can attest to, it is that managers lie. The next five months of my life I became nocturnal.</p>

<p>The Shift</p>

<p>I live in Queens, New York, and I worked there during this time as well. During the day, the borough bustles with activity, especially on the busy street the mall I worked at was located. I would be getting ready for work at the same time everyone else was going to sleep for work the next day. While other people were tired, I was wide awake from the coffee I would have at around 10:00 PM at night.</p>

<p>Cities have a different character at night. When you’re walking the streets alone in the dark, you become aware of every sound. Every car passing, every siren blasting.</p>

<p>I remember walking down the streets of my neighborhood, trying to walk quickly to get to the bus stop so I wouldn’t have to wait an hour for the next bus. I remember for every person that passed me, I wondered if they were like me, working a job they hated that forced them to stay awake after hours.</p>

<p>I remember a feeling of paranoia that would sometimes come over me while I was on an empty bus. I couldn’t explain it, but I always felt like in the darkness, someone or something was watching me. I sometimes felt like the darkness itself was judging me. “Look what your life has come to.”</p>

<p>Then after getting to the store, I saw the last of the day time workers getting ready to leave. Sometimes they would have to stay, because the store was a mess and there were eighty stacks of jeans that needed to be folded properly. Before actually getting into my duties for the day, I would help them finish so they could leave before midnight.</p>

<p>And then my actual work began. If we got only fifty boxes of merchandise, it would be a light night. My shift ran from 11 PM to 7 AM most of the time, however I would rarely be leaving at 7. Most of the time, we would have to stay in order to complete all of our tasks. Those tasks were opening the boxes, folding the merchandise, censoring the merchandise, and finding somewhere to put the merchandise. Whether it was on the sales floor or in the stockroom.</p>

<p>Most of the time it would go to the stockroom. A cramped, fluorescent lit room filled with merchandise and marketing tools. It was the dustiest room I have ever seen. The first time I spent any amount of time there, I actually got sick. I still went to work the next night, because I needed the money. There were mouse traps in every corner, there were probably other vermin around as well. Mice and cockroaches are just as native to New York as New Yorkers are, after all.</p>

<p>Photo by Wes Hicks on Unsplash
The shelves were extremely high up, filled to the brim with clothes. One night, all the clothes on one shelf fell because someone crashed into the shelf. Dozens of women’s shirts and sweaters were on the floor. I had to pick them up, fold them and put them back. When I asked for help, the person I asked looked like they wanted to quit right then and there.</p>

<p>The censoring was the worst part. They didn’t want us sitting down, because that would ‘slow us down’ in the words of management. I would be bent over, taking a little needle and putting it through the seam of a shirt or a pair of jeans. I lost count of the amount of times I’ve accidentally stabbed myself in my fingers. I never got blood on the clothes, but maybe someone else did.</p>

<p>Working in that stockroom taught me a valuable lesson. Whenever I buy clothes from anywhere, I will wash it before I wear it.</p>

<p>Photo by Anna Dziubinska on Unsplash
When the shift finally ended, probably closer to 8 or 9 than 7, we would leave. And I would see the sun for the first time all day. It had a funny effect of making me more miserable, because I was so tired and hungry and just wanted to sleep, but the sun being high in the sky tricked my brain into wanting to stay awake.</p>

<p>And then I would go home, at around 9:30 AM, and fall asleep. I would wake up at around 4:30–5, and then do it all again.</p>

<p>The Effects</p>

<p>Human beings are not meant to be up at that hour, let alone actually staying up through the night. Our circadian rhythms naturally line up with the cycle of day of night. Staying up that late, through the night, even with four cups of black coffee, took a great deal of effort. Light-exposure basically keeps the body awake and alert, and as night time comes, our bodies get prepared for sleep.</p>

<p>When most people think of circadian rhythms, they probably think of their sleeping habits. However, circadian rhythms also affect a lot more than just sleeping patterns. Digestion is also affected by the circadian rhythm. Poor sleeping habits have been linked to gastrointestinal problems.</p>

<p>Photo by Mpho Mojapelo on Unsplash
As a personal anecdote, when I was on these night shifts, I was also in every other way obsessed with my health. I would exercise every day, meticulously track my calories, and track my progress across each workout. As I look back on those days, I barely made any progress in strength or conditioning. In fact, I even gained 15 lbs while I was on these shifts. It wasn’t 15 lbs of muscle either, despite what I told myself.</p>

<p>As another personal anecdote, on days when I did not work, I found it difficult to actually sleep. At night, when I wasn’t working, I fell asleep easily, but I did not stay asleep easily. Restless would be the best term to use for my sleeping habits.</p>

<p>The World Health Organization classified night shift work as a potential carcinogen. Proper sleeping habits are so important for health and quality of life.</p>

<p>After six months of these shifts, I asked to go back down to the morning/afternoon/anything-but-night shifts. I couldn’t take those night shifts anymore. Management agreed, and I never looked back.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="personal" /><category term="post" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was November of 2017. Eleven months after graduating from college, I was working in the job of nobody’s dreams: retail stock associate. Holiday season was fast approaching, and my manager at work approached me to ask a simple question.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photoshop Youtube</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/photoshop/2023/09/22/photoshop_youtube.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photoshop Youtube" /><published>2023-09-22T18:53:33-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-22T18:53:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/photoshop/2023/09/22/photoshop_youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/photoshop/2023/09/22/photoshop_youtube.html"><![CDATA[<p>In around July of 2020, I purchased a subscription to the Adobe Creative Cloud in order to start learning more about Photoshop. My original goal was to learn a little bit about photo editing: color correction, portrait retouching, that kind of stuff. I had just returned to work after the Covid lockdowns were beginning to loosen up, was absolutely miserable at that job, and wanted a bit of a new creative outlet.</p>

<p>I dabbled in photoshop in college, but I really wanted to dive deep into the software and learn the ins and outs. And in order to do that, I went to YouTube. In my first few days, I found this video.</p>

<p>I was stunned when I watched that video. Watching that changed my view of what I could do with photoshop. I was introduced to photo manipulation as an artform. The four artists in the video became my photoshop heroes. I found other artists, but these four were the ones that I looked up to the most.</p>

<p>Nemanja Sekulic</p>

<p>The first artist featured in the video is photographer and digital artist Nemanja Sekulic. I was originally impressed by his science fiction and fantasy photo manipulations. Seeing his work was particularly astonishing for me, because it was exactly what I wanted to achieve with photoshop but didn’t think was possible. His YouTube channel had many tutorials, which when I started photo manipulation I treated like training wheels, in that before I was comfortable making my own artwork, I would follow his work.</p>

<p>PixImperfect</p>

<p>When somebody first opens up Photoshop, they will be greeted with an interface that is probably more than a little intimidating. There will be so many tools and pages and buttons. A few thoughts will be going through someone’s mind. What is an adjustment layer versus an adjustment? How do I make somebody’s hair green? What is a blending mode? What is a mask?</p>

<p>Unmesh Dinda is the creator of the YouTube page PixImperfect, and when I was learning how to actually use the tools in Photoshop, his channel was the first stop. His photoshop tutorials are perfectly explained in such a way that anybody who has never even opened up photoshop could use at least a few tools after watching a few of his videos.</p>

<p>Benny Productions</p>

<p>Benny Productions is the channel for Dutch photoshop wizard Benjamin van Valen. The first thing I thought when I saw him, and saw his techniques for rim lightning, was “that is genius”.</p>

<p>But then I saw his “realistified” series, and was flabbergasted by what he was able to accomplish with Photoshop. He basically took an illustration one of his fans would make, and make a ‘realistic’ version of it using stock images.</p>

<p>I think another thing I really appreciated about Benny was the photoshop battles series, where I was introduced to a lot of other artists. I saw their techniques, and tried to copy them/learn from them as best as I could. It felt like the door to a new world was opened when I found his channel.</p>

<p>Imad Awan</p>

<p>Imad Awan is a concept artist and illustrator who utilizes photo manipulation in a technique called photobashing. Photobashing is using a combination of stock images and digital painting techniques to create artwork. It’ll usually have a painterly feel to it, but some or all of the assets in the artwork will have originated from stock photos or 3D assets.</p>

<p>Imad Awan is an amazing artist, and his artwork originally appealed to me because I’m a huge fantasy nerd, and his work was obviously inspired by fantasy works like Lord of the Rings. I can’t draw to save my life, but his techniques in photobashing really helped my own work.</p>

<p>The Rise and Fall of the Photo Manipulation Community</p>

<p>‘Rise and fall’ is absolutely an exaggeration.</p>

<p>At the time I entered the space, photo manipulation blew up in popularity. Videos from the above creators, and others, were getting millions of views. The community was vibrant on places like Instagram and Twitter, and other art specific websites like Behance and (to a much lesser degree) DeviantArt.</p>

<p>Videos and speed arts about Photoshop content would get a huge amount of views, some of them breaking 1 million. People were watching tutorials, sharing their art online, and it was a great time to be an artist.</p>

<p>One of the most popular videos from this time frame.
I was a tiny fish in a large pond. My instagram page had at its peak less than 100 followers, but it still felt like I was a part of a vibrant community of digital artists who were all committed to the same growth and on the same journey.</p>

<p>After a few years, however, the online community of photo manipulation has slowed down tremendously. The upload frequency of the big time photo manipulation channels dropped tremendously, as did their view counts. Their Instagram pages, like most Instagram pages nowadays, are infrequently updated.</p>

<p>As someone who was in the community, I have a few theories.</p>

<p>The first one is the most obvious to me. This time period I was talking about was the period of the pandemic, more people were spending time inside on their computer. A lot of people took up hobbies like digital art in order to alleviate boredom. Once the restrictions loosened up, more people were going out more, and thus spending less time on their computers.</p>

<p>The second one is that a lot of the top dogs of the community weren’t full time content creators. They were full time artists who did content creation on the side. They had jobs, they had client work, they had personal projects. Content, especially videos, take up a lot of free time.</p>

<p>The third one is that the community was overtaken by AI created works. Not to get too far into anti-AI, but I do remember a time when every recommended post on my Instagram was an AI generated image. The first time you see one, you think “wow that looks really beautiful! Whoa, AI created that?” The fiftieth time you see it, you start to wonder where all the human artists went.</p>

<p>This was around the time I distanced myself from the space, but I do remember AI splitting the community. Some people thought it was a mockery of artistic talent, and other people thought it was the future.</p>

<p>The photo manipulation community isn’t dead, but it also isn’t on obvious platforms like Facebook, YouTube, Instagram and Twitter. I’ve been around the internet long enough to know that there are platforms out there where the reach is smaller, but the community is still active and encouraging. Photo manipulation is an old art, almost as old as photography itself, and it isn’t going away any time soon. It predates the actual Photoshop software, and there will always be room for it.</p>

<p>I think I was drawn to it because I was always a pretty bad artist, but I had an eye for visuals and always wanted to explore it. The idea of stitching together elements from different photographs reminded me of the way that dreams work. Different memories combined together into a new one, whether it is a memory that came from fantasy, or a memory that showcases the beauty of everyday life.</p>

<p>Photo manipulation was the only art form I actually excelled at. I can’t draw at all, despite trying multiple times to learn. My painting ability can best be described as ‘abstract’.</p>

<p>Every creative has an initial spark, something that makes them say “I want to do that!” Maybe it’s a movie, a book, a song, a piece of art so beautiful and astonishing it lingers in their minds years after seeing it. Maybe they saw it as a child and it led them to a lifelong journey of artistry, or maybe they saw it well into their adult lives and it led them to starting their art journey a little later. No matter what happens, internally or externally, that spark will always be there.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="photoshop" /><category term="post" /><category term="photoshop" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In around July of 2020, I purchased a subscription to the Adobe Creative Cloud in order to start learning more about Photoshop. My original goal was to learn a little bit about photo editing: color correction, portrait retouching, that kind of stuff. I had just returned to work after the Covid lockdowns were beginning to loosen up, was absolutely miserable at that job, and wanted a bit of a new creative outlet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gamestop’s Crypto Push</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/2023/09/10/gamestop_crypto.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gamestop’s Crypto Push" /><published>2023-09-10T18:53:33-04:00</published><updated>2023-09-10T18:53:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/2023/09/10/gamestop_crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/2023/09/10/gamestop_crypto.html"><![CDATA[<p>It was around 2008 when my Playstation3 stopped working. I was 14 years old. My machine got the yellow light of death, and I had sent it to a video game repair company to try to fix it. They weren’t able to, and thanks to my teenage mind’s inability to figure out online payments, never even got my console back (but I also never paid for it!).</p>

<p>I remember my mom got me an XBox 360, and that became my console of choice for the seventh video game generation. Wanting some new games for it, I took all the PS3 games I had, I can’t remember how many but it was a significant amount (at least seven or eight), and took it to a local GameStop.</p>

<p>I think I got one XBox 360 game, Burnout Paradise, for all those PS3 games.</p>

<p>I’ve been reluctant to go to a GameStop ever since.</p>

<p>Fast forward a few years, I’m working in a mall that also contains a GameStop. Occasionally I’d go in to look at games and see if I could buy one, but with the digital age of gaming, it would just be easier to buy them online if I even wanted to play them. It would be cheaper too, because of frequent sales. GameStop never had sales going on, at least none that I could see, except for major holidays.</p>

<p>I am not a fan of GameStop as a company. I never was a fan of the company. The workers were all knowledgeable and friendly, but the actual merchandise inside was overpriced and the actual trade-in of physical games wasn’t consumer friendly. With digital games growing in popularity, it seemed like GameStop would go the way of Blockbuster: a relic of a bygone era.</p>

<p>In recent years, however, GameStop has transformed from a dying company to the fixation of meme stock trading. It has been a fascinating transformation.</p>

<p>Photo by Clay Banks on Unsplash
A meme stock is a stock that gained notoriety through the usage of social media. It is not a kind term, it is usually used for stocks that are venerated on forums like Reddit’s r/wallstreetbets. In January of 2021, the video game retailer GameStop became one of the most recognizable meme stocks in the world when it was the center of a now infamous short squeeze.</p>

<p>NFTs are non-fungible tokens, a way of identifying digital ownership on a blockchain. In February of 2021, the NFT market exploded in popularity after digital artist Beeple sold his work, ‘Everydays: the First 5000 Days’ for millions of dollars. Every artist/celebrity started purchasing NFTs in the hopes of making that kind of money.</p>

<p>Cryptocurrency and meme stocks have a lot of overlap because both are highly speculative and highly volatile, and they both have dedicated online communities with a lot of overlap.</p>

<p>After the short squeeze, GameStop’s trajectory as a company changed. It was no longer trying to just be a video game retailer. Leadership wanted to change it to become a more tech focused company. It leaned into its new reputation on the internet.</p>

<p>A few months before the short squeeze, in August of 2020, investment company RC Ventures purchased 9% stakes in GameStop. RC Ventures is managed by Ryan Cohen, who was previously CEO of pet retailer Chewy. Cohen became Executive Chairman of GameStop, and under his leadership the company underwent a drastic restructuring.</p>

<p>Ryan Cohen
In February of 2021, GameStop appointed Matt Francis to the newly created Chief Technology Officer. In March of 2021, Jenna Owens was appointed to be Chief Operating Officer. Just a month later, Elliot Wilke was appointed as Chief Growth Officer. In June 2021, Mike Recupero was appointed as Chief Financial Officer.</p>

<p>And in the same month, former Amazon executive Matt Furlong was named as Chief Executive Officer of GameStop, replacing George Sherman. With new leadership, GameStop began a venture into the cryptocurrency/NFT market in order to transform itself.</p>

<p>It hit its first bump in October of 2021, when Owens left the company after a “separation agreement”. By the end of the third quarter 2021, GameStop reported losses of over $100 million.</p>

<p>But the company was just beginning its transformation, so some road blocks were to be expected.</p>

<p>GameStop announced in 2022 a partnership with Immutable, a blockchain gaming company. In Immutable’s own words on the company website, “Immutable is a global leader in gaming on a mission to bring digital ownership to every player by making it safe and easy to build great web3 games.”</p>

<p>Immutable logo
This partnership was to launch GameStop’s NFT marketplace, which would launch in 2022. The company was still losing money, but another thing happened outside of the company’s control that would doom the NFT push.</p>

<p>The public consensus against NFTs shifted. The concept of scarcity in a digital art world would be pretty baffling to anyone who knows how to copy and save images, so the concept was always subject to mockery. Beyond that, as more people began to learn more about NFTs, the more public opinion turned against them.</p>

<p>The negative environmental impact of cryptocurrency, the news that some NFTs were stolen from artists who were not selling them, the various schemes and scams that were going around. YouTube videos critical of NFTs earned millions of views.</p>

<p>12 million views as of September 2023
As someone who was in the digital art world at the time, it was rather interesting to see artists who were heavily pushing NFTs slowly distance themselves from them. It was as if everyone decided that the less said about their embarrassing NFT phase, the better. NFTs were no longer the next big thing, they were a fad that died down when public opinion turned against them.</p>

<p>By the time GameStop finally launched their NFT platform, nft.gamestop.com, in the middle of 2022, the market for NFTs collapsed.</p>

<p>You can probably guess how GameStop’s NFT venture panned out, but to sumarize: the company is going to pull away from cryptocurrency in November of this year. Matt Furlong was ousted as CEO. The company is still in the same position it was in since the short squeeze that (temporarily) changed the company’s direction.</p>

<p>What is next for GameStop? Ryan Cohen is executive chairman, and he does seem to still believe in the company. Its reputation in the online stock trading community has not wavered. In fact, they’re as dedicated as ever to the company, and GameStop is not going away anytime soon. But what direction the company should go in a world of digital gaming is also uncertain.</p>

<p>And I think that’s what makes this story so compelling in my view. I’m not viewing GameStop from the perspective of someone who loved the store. At no point in my life did I love GameStop. I have a vendetta against them that goes back fifteen years. However, through researching GameStop’s struggles to find an identity in an ever changing world, I found myself strangely relating to this corporation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="post" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was around 2008 when my Playstation3 stopped working. I was 14 years old. My machine got the yellow light of death, and I had sent it to a video game repair company to try to fix it. They weren’t able to, and thanks to my teenage mind’s inability to figure out online payments, never even got my console back (but I also never paid for it!).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Phishing: Fake Job Postings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/phishing/awareness/2023/06/05/phishing_job.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phishing: Fake Job Postings" /><published>2023-06-05T18:53:33-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T18:53:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/phishing/awareness/2023/06/05/phishing_job</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/phishing/awareness/2023/06/05/phishing_job.html"><![CDATA[<p>Around this time last year, I was a graphic designer and video editor. And one thing I learned while working in that field and trying to find freelance or W2 work, was that there were a lot of fake job postings.</p>

<p>I would apply for a seemingly legitimate looking position. “Graphic Designer at X Marketing”, for example. A small company that I have never heard of, but they seem legitimate at a first glance. The qualifications/requirements weren’t ridiculous, the pay was good, it was a remote position, the job posting seemed like a dream come true. And then, a few days later, I would get an email from the company.</p>

<p>And every red flag went straight up.</p>

<p>The email would have poor grammar, the email address deliberately misspelled, an immediate job offer without an interview. Requiring that you click on a link in the email, requiring that you download some software through a link in the email, and a dozen more red flags that I can’t even remember.</p>

<p>It wasn’t until I did a cybersecurity bootcamp that I learned there was an actual term for this, and it is called ‘phishing.’</p>

<p>Phishing is a type of attack where a malicious actor attempts to gain personal information, usually by posing as someone else, or a legitimate organization, and contacting their targets through email. Emails that say something like “You Just Won $100,000!”, text messages that say “Your Netflix Account is on hold, please click here to verify your payment info.”</p>

<p>In the case of a fake job posting, the sensitive information they probably want is a social security number, since being employed by any company requires that information. They most likely want it for other identity theft schemes. Other sensitive information could be your passwords, credit card numbers, or even complete control over your computer. If the fake job posting is for an in-person job, however, the consequences can and probably will be more severe.</p>

<p>In my own experience looking for work as a designer, at some points it seemed like every other job posting was going to lead to a phishing scam. If I look through my email, I could probably find a dozen of them. It has been less severe in my search for a role in cybersecurity, but I do think there are still a few fake job postings I have accidentally applied for. I think there are a few reasons for these fake job postings.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>A lot of people who are job hunting are going to be looking for a long time. As of this writing, I have been looking for a job for at least two and a half months, and if you go on LinkedIn you’ll find plenty of posts from people who have been looking for a lot longer. That is a long time to be a target.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A lot of people apply indiscriminately to job postings without actually reading the job requirements. I myself am guilty of this, but on sites like Indeed and LinkedIn, there are job postings where you can submit an application with just a click of a button. Pretty much every single fake job posting I’ve come across has been some variation of ‘easy apply’. For every fake job posting I’ve gotten a response for, when I actually looked at the posting carefully, I thought to myself “how could I think this was real?”</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>-This is just anecdotal, but when I’m job hunting for weeks and months on end without hearing any results, it is a strange euphoria when I actually do get a response. When that response is actually positive, it almost turns off any sense of danger that I might have.</p>

<p>Luckily I have never fallen for these schemes and I can usually spot them pretty easily. I have a mental list of things I look out for when I get a response I believe is for a fake company, or a fake posting.</p>

<p>Poor grammar — This is usually the first thing I notice when I’m reading their emails. Missing punctuation, misspelled words, using words incorrectly.</p>

<p>You can’t find the person on LinkedIn — The first thing I do when I receive an email regarding a job is to look the person up on LinkedIn.</p>

<p>Misspelled email address — sometimes I applied for companies that are actually real, and an attacker is pretending to be from that company. If that is the case, one of the biggest tells is to look at the email address. It is usually slightly misspelled. For example, @xdigitalmarketing as the legitimate email, @xdigtalmarketing as the phishing email.</p>

<p>Job offer without an interview — this one kind of goes without saying, but I did one time get a job offer (complete with salary and benefits!) after just applying to the posting. I don’t think it’s controversial to say that every employer is going to want to talk to a prospective employee before hiring them, no matter how amazing their resume may seem.</p>

<p>They want your social security number — if before even interviewing you, they are mentioning your social security number, run away.</p>

<p>They mention credit scores — I once got an email that mentioned my credit score needed to be above a certain number to work for their company.</p>

<p>None of these things, on their own, would be a huge cause for alarm, except for the last three. However, for fake job emails, I usually see a few of them together.</p>

<p>If you’re having trouble figuring out if a job posting is fake or not, in my experience if there is something about it that doesn’t look right, doing my research on the company will usually prove it to be real. Just personally speaking, if something looks too good to be true, it probably is too good to be true.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="phishing" /><category term="awareness" /><category term="post" /><category term="phishing" /><category term="awareness" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around this time last year, I was a graphic designer and video editor. And one thing I learned while working in that field and trying to find freelance or W2 work, was that there were a lot of fake job postings.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Can you cheat while hacking? Jangow Walkthrough</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/2023/06/05/jangow_walkthrough.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can you cheat while hacking? Jangow Walkthrough" /><published>2023-06-05T18:53:33-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-05T18:53:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/2023/06/05/jangow_walkthrough</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/cyber-turtle/post/hacking/2023/06/05/jangow_walkthrough.html"><![CDATA[<p>Can You Cheat While Hacking? Jangow Walkthrough
I want to get back into hacking. Jangow is a vulnerable machine rated as ‘easy’ on Vulnhub, so in order to get back into hacking I figured that a machine like that would be perfect.</p>

<p>In a Capture the Flag like this, there are two flags to get. The first flag is the user flag, and the second is when the hacker gets to the root user.</p>

<p>I first created a directory specifically for this machine. I wanted to make sure I put all the files in the same place, and document all my findings.</p>

<p>The next step in this CTF was to get the IP address and make sure it was on the same network as my Kali Linux machine. I know the IP address was in the log in screen, but I did want to do it in a more “official” way. I did this using a simple nmap scan of the network.</p>

<p>After I did that, I also saw that two ports were open. FTP on port 21 and HTTP on port 80. I then tried to see if I could log in to the FTP anonymously. Anonymous FTP logins use the username anonymous and any password, sometimes the anonymous user’s email as a way of documenting who is coming in and out.</p>

<p>That didn’t work, so my next step was to check out the HTTP website. I inspected the page source for any kind of comments in the HTML and JavaScript, but there was nothing there.</p>

<p>Bootstrap is a CSS framework, a way of easily formatting the appearance of a website.</p>

<p>I noticed there was a link on the website to a page called “buscar”. I remembered enough Spanish to recognize it as such, but didn’t remember enough to translate (sorry to all my Spanish teachers from fifth grade to high school).</p>

<p>This looked like this was a way of remote code execution, but I did want to gather a little bit more info.</p>

<p>To do that, I first used nmap -sV to get the service versions of the FTP and HTTP, to see if there were any vulnerabilities.</p>

<p>I then did a dirb scan of the website, although I will admit that I didn’t take a look at this afterwards.</p>

<p>My next move was to actually open up Burpsuite and intercept a request on that buscar page, to play around with it and test if my theory was correct. I opened up the browser in Burpsuite, intercepted a request, and sent it to the repeater.</p>

<p>My theory was correct. I executed whoami, and I got back ‘www-data’. I tested out a few more commands, and I used https://www.urlencoder.org/ to encode them.</p>

<p>I got the /etc/passwd file, and saw the user jangow01. I checked out the /home directory, and saw that this user had a directory. I looked inside, and I found the user.txt flag. Encoding the command to open up that user.txt, I got the first flag.</p>

<p>Important to know the version, and this comes to play later
Next step was to try to establish a more permanent presence. I first tried to do this by establish a reverse shell.</p>

<p>I have absolutely no idea why, but nothing I did worked. I first tried to do it through executing it through the URL, but that failed.</p>

<p>So I took a look around and found this config.php file in a wordpress directory.</p>

<p>Maybe those were the same credentials for the FTP?</p>

<p>I tried to log in, first with that username and password, but that failed. I then used jangow01, and managed to get in.</p>

<p>The next few steps were quite frustrating, because they were trying to establish a shell on the target machine, and each one failed.</p>

<p>I first made a bash script on my Kali machine, used the FTP credentials to put it in the /tmp directory of the target machine and confirmed that it was on the target machine.</p>

<p>Pro-Tip: Don’t name your reverse shell script ‘reverse_shell.sh’.
When I tried to execute that file, it still failed.</p>

<p>So at a loss, I decided to do one thing I didn’t really want to do when I started this, but it was quite necessary at this stage, because I had no idea why my efforts to establish a shell weren’t working.</p>

<p>I logged in through the actual machine. Is that cheating? I don’t know, but I did it anyway.</p>

<p>So having (technically) gotten access, I resolved to get to root. Through, researching the kernel version, I found this exploit for this kernel version. I downloaded it to my Kali machine first, compiled it on my kali machine, and used FTP to get it on the target machine.</p>

<p>I don’t think ‘normal_elf’ is a particularly good name for malicious binaries either
However, there were a few bumps in the road.</p>

<p>First, while on the Jangow machine, I couldn’t use the ‘/’ key. When executing a binary, you need to type ‘./binary_name’. So that was the first problem.</p>

<p>I managed to figure out a way around this, but to my chagrin I got the “version ‘glibc_2.34’ not found”. In this scenario, this just means I shouldn’t have compiled this binary on my Kali machine.</p>

<p>So I went through this again, except I just put the source code on the target machine and compiled it there.</p>

<p>But how did I get around not being able to use the ‘/’ key?</p>

<p>I compiled the source code, which the output was a file named ‘a.out’. I don’t know why, but I wasn’t able to name the output file. I had to figure out a way to get ‘./a.out’ into the command line. I used the find command, and outputted the results of that to a text file.</p>

<p>I then opened up the text file, and then used this ‘$(!!)’ to execute ‘./a.out’. This executed the a.out file, and I finally got to root.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><category term="post" /><category term="hacking" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Can You Cheat While Hacking? Jangow Walkthrough I want to get back into hacking. Jangow is a vulnerable machine rated as ‘easy’ on Vulnhub, so in order to get back into hacking I figured that a machine like that would be perfect.]]></summary></entry></feed>